# Joshua**Bowles**

Founder All Group, Software Engineer

### contact

jbowles@ailgroup.io github linkedin ailgroup.io

# academic interests

computational math, data engineering, machine learning, scalable systems

# programming

Go, Julia, Rust, Ruby, Python

# professional focus

State-of-the-art technology and industry proven techniques. Advocate for solutions that balance innovation with proven techniques. Proven track record of building internal infrastructure and technology for start-ups in quick growth periods yielding high profit returns. I'm a specialist in helping companies utilize machine learning techniques in ways that optimize return on investment.

# education

**M.Sc.** Computational Mathematics Texas A&M University, College Station, TX Geometric Probability and Numerical Analysis

2006–2008 M.A. Linguistics University Of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

Amazonian Languages and Computational Linguistics

2000–2006 B.A. English, Logic, Linguistics Metropolitan State College of Denver, Denver, CO

Logic, Literature, and Cognitive Science

## recent

2018-Now Skipio

Senior Software Engineer

- Backend distributed systems for text messaging—Ruby
- · Sentiment and spam classifiers-Go, Julia
- · Message Clustering-Julia

#### 2018-Now Asymmetric Information Logics Group

Founder, CSTO

- · Applying for Non-Profit status
- Research and application for geometric deep learning models for massive high-dimensional data
- Research and application on logic-based classical knowledge engineering architectures

#### 

Software Architect

- Distributed file-system infrastructure and machine learning algorithms for hotel matching—Go
- API and DB schema to distribute application payloads to business intelligence—Go, Ruby
- Deep-learning model for room-type categorization (proof-of-concept, never deployed)—**Go, Python**
- Machine learning classification system for 3rd party cancellation policies and error categorization—Go, Ruby

# **experience**

#### 2014-2016 **TravelPass**

Senior Software Engineer

- Multi-provider platform for travel industry (API proxy to Expedia, Travelocity, Orbtiz, Priceline, etc...)—Ruby
- Hypermedia API for 3rd party integrators (used by 3 PHP websites and multiple call-centers)—Ruby
- · Built data schema for business intelligence-Ruby
- Algorithm and schema for matching custom hotel data in real time— Ruby

#### 2010-2014 One on One

Software Engineer

- Data pipeline to consume inventory distribution from machine learning scoring system—Ruby
- Data pipeline system to push machine learning lead generation scoring data to business intelligence—NodeJS, Ruby
- API for lead scoring model—NodeJS
- · Helped evaluate modeling for lead generation profile scoring-Ruby, R
- Automated bid-system; prototypes for a keyword classification tool and ontology for SEO-Ruby
- Designed new tracking-code system using parsing-expressiongrammar—Ruby
- Maintain and optimize ETL process using Redis and MySQL for Business Intelligence—Ruby

#### 2008-2009 Attensity

Linguist, Software Engineer

- Ruby, Python, C++ programming
- Text processing and building lexicons
- · Named entity recognition
- developed methods for parsing fixed phrases and idioms

# tools

Varying degrees of proficiency:

- PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Oracle, Redis, MongoDB, HBase, Memcached, Groupcache, LMDB
- Docker, AWS (RDS, S3, EC2, Elasticache, SQS), Heroku (Redis, Metabase, PostgreSQL)
- VIM, VSCode, Emacs
- MacOS, Linux (Ubuntu, PopOS!, CentOS, ArchLinux)
- R, F#, LISP, Prolog, Haskell, Elixir, Clojure, Scala
- · Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-Learn, OpenCV, MxNet